www.Caleb Provost.com

Louisville, KY 40241 | 920 509 9645 | Caleb.I.Provost@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/CalebProvost

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Self-motivated professional Engineer able to apply principles and techniques to research, design, develop, and test solutions for complex software, electronics hardware, and general computing applications. Constantly improving skills and learning new techniques through hobbies and studies in embedded system development.

EDUCATION

- BS in Engineering Technology-Computers
 DeVry University Addison, IL CGPA: 3.67/4.00
- Front End Web Development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript)
 Code Louisville Louisville, KY

SKILLS

- Systems Analysis/Testing
- Electronics Testing, & Repair
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript
- Visual Studio IDE
- Altera Quartus II
- Data Analysis
- Norton Ghost
- Git/GitHub
- NI Multisim
- Java/EclipseFilezilla
- MySQL

MATLAB

- NI LabVIEW
 - TI CCStudio C/C++
- C/C!
- VS Code IDE
- PuTTY

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

- Object-Oriented Programming
- Application Programming
- Signal Processing
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Introduction to Database
- Electronic Circuits & Devices I, II, III
- Digital Circuits & Systems
- Product Development
- Embedded Microprocessor Systems
- Technology Integration I, II
- Structured Programming
- Data Communications & Networking
- Microprocessor Interfacing
- Digital Fundamentals & Eng. Tech.
- Microprocessor Architecture

PROJECTS

- Custom CSS Web Profile (1st Front End Dev)
- Mobile Embedded System Handheld ("Project Catena")
- Bootstrap focused Web Profile (<u>calebprovost.com</u>)
- JavaScript Interactive Color Game (<u>ColorGame</u>)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

<u>Grindmaster – Electrolux subsidiary</u> R&D Engineering Technologists Louisville, KY

August 2018 - Present

- Accomplishments:
 - Used my cultural understanding and Korean to reestablished business between Grindmaster and Korea Testing Laboratory (KTL).
 - Saved payroll \$6,000 per month by fabricating and programming test equipment used with unit reliability testing.
 - Created a Risk Assessment system that auto generates reports, saving 5 hours of assessment per unit.
 - Developed a \$4,000 data acquisition system with a team for use on unit and compliance testing.
 - Unit tested prototype systems and root cause evaluated failures and bugs.
 - o Assisted Production to meet quarterly quotas through cross-departmental product and system maintenance.
 - Reinstated UL international certification by writing 17025 compliance management system and procedures.
 - o Worked directly with Lead Product Engineers for research, testing, quality analysis, and other R&D work.
 - o Trusted with Company Purchase Card to acquire latest laboratory equipment.
- Additional Duties:
 - o Modified, maintained, and repaired electronics equipment and systems to ensure proper function.
 - o Replaced defective components and parts using precision instruments and hand tools.
 - o Developed and maintained design, testing, and test reports, operational records, logs, and documentation.
 - o Assembled circuitry for systems according to engineering instructions and/or technical manuals.
 - o Inspected newly produced or installed equipment to verify, adjust, or correct operating problems.
 - Diagnosed and troubleshoot instruments, equipment, and systems, using electronic test equipment (multi-meters, oscilloscopes, etc.).
 - o Communicated technical results and records of tests for management, team, lab personnel, and customers.

www.Caleb Provost.com

Louisville, KY 40241 | 920 509 9645 | Caleb.I.Provost@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/CalebProvost

Page two – PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Kentuckiana Comfort Company

Louisville, KY

April 2018 - August 2018

HVAC Electronics Technician

- Accomplishments:
 - Scored in top 1% during company's electronics evaluation.
 - Apart of a team which lead in production quota ranking.
- Additional Duties:
 - o Evaluated electronic schematics and acquired necessary tools and equipment for circuit assembly.
 - o Responsible for installing and maintaining the electrical components in a 10 to 20 ton HVAC system, including all electrical wiring, controls, and other climate-control systems.
 - Evaluated work orders and planned accordingly.
 - o Performed six sigma and industry standard 5S requirements.

<u>Flex</u> Louisville, KY January 2017 – April 2018

Engineering Technician

- Accomplishments:
 - o Evaluated electronic schematics and acquired necessary tools and equipment for circuit assembly.
 - Responsible for installing and maintaining the electrical components in a 10 to 20 ton HVAC system, including all electrical wiring, controls, and other climate-control systems.
 - Evaluated work orders and planned accordingly.
 - o Perform six sigma and industry standard 5S requirements.
- Additional Duties:
 - Replaced defective components and parts with precision instruments.
 - Ascertained customer requirements and offered solutions.
 - o Maintained electronic equipment.
 - Tested performance of operations and equipment.
 - o Documented operational procedures.
 - o Assembled equipment or components.
 - o Inspected finished products to locate flaws.

- o Provided technical guidance to other personnel.
- Selected tools, equipment, and technologies for operational use.
- o Determined causes of operational failures.
- o Trained personnel on proper operational procedures.
- Maintained and queried databases.
- Assisted in quality control activities.
- o Assisted engineers with LEAN/Six Sigma research.
- o Estimated resource requirements for production projects.

Teach and Learn in Korea (TaLK)

Republic of Korea

August 2014 – July 2016

TaLK Scholar

- Accomplishments:
 - o Travelled to every Provence (and almost all major cities) in Korea.
 - o Hiked the tallest peak in Korea.
 - Ate new and exotic foods like live octopus!
 - o Taught over 40 students how to speak English (elementary level).
 - Additional Duties:
 - o Acted as an ambassador for the United States of America while in South Korea and its education system.
 - o Performed community leadership roles, leading with exemplary behavior and a work ethic that encouraged the increased growth of the 'TaLK' Program.
 - o Fostered successful and engaging ESL classes using practicum, hands-on classes, and various cultural activities, all while performing 'TaLK' Scholar duties provided by the schools and Local Provincial Office of Education.
 - o Performed extracurricular activities to improve the student's education; Introduction to C++ programming among
 - Engineered new and engaging ways to perform studies and complete school tasks during personal time.